<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feed on Atharva&#39;s Personal Page</title>
    <link>atharva.social/feed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feed on Atharva&#39;s Personal Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:51:03 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="atharva.social/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Process and Tests</title>
      <link>atharva.social/feed/processandtests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:51:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>atharva.social/feed/processandtests/</guid>
      <description>A test evaluates the outcome of a process.
A good way to know if a system is not doing well is if the process is designed around the test, or to put it more bluntly, the process is hacked to optimize for the test.1
Examples that come to mind:
 Schools, where teaching is more about making students do well in their test rather than sharing knowledge and making people curious and critical thinkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Vim</title>
      <link>atharva.social/feed/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 17:04:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>atharva.social/feed/vim/</guid>
      <description>A lot has been said about Vim by programmers. For something that is just yet another fancy hammer to help construct a program, too much has been said about it.
Yet I found most of it not constructive to my personal experience of using Vim. Too many people take an extreme position and vehemently speak for or against it, most likely because it becomes a belief attached to their identity, much like a religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Controversial Opinion: Internet Shutdowns</title>
      <link>atharva.social/feed/internet-shutdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 13:45:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>atharva.social/feed/internet-shutdown/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;d think it&amp;rsquo;s easy to agree that internet shutdowns are an uncontroversially terrible idea, except the Indian Government loves to do them so much, that I don&amp;rsquo;t even know anymore.
Human rights violations and suppression of freedom reasons aside — it is still so painfully destructive. Economic productivity is ruined and a lot of critical systems rely on the internet. It causes more chaos as information is no more easily verifiable and people would rely more on hearsay.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>